Guide to the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace pamphlet and microfilm collection, 1817-1950 MS2110
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
Carnegie Endowment for International Peace pamphlet and microfilm collection
1817-1950
Special Collections Research Center, The George Washington University
MS2110
65 Linear Feet
The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace was founded in 1910 by Andrew Carnegie. The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, which since 1983 has again been headquartered in Washington, D.C., continues the work begun by its founders. Elihu Root and Nicholas Murray Butler were activists in a segment of a larger peace movement both in the U.S. and abroad that had its roots in the later years of the nineteenth century. This collection consists of over 7,200 items of bound pamphlets, unbound pamphlets, and microfilm. They range in date from 1817 to 1950. The topics cover world wars, international treaties and other important world events.
Restrictions on Access
Some records may be restricted.
Acquisition Information
Gelman Library purchased this collection in 1950
Historical or Biographical Note
The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace was founded in 1910 by Andrew Carnegie (1835-1919), who transferred to 28 selected trustees the sum of $10 million in bonds, the revenue of which was to be used to "hasten the abolition of international war." Two of the trustees, Elihu Root and Nicholas Murray Butler were very important figures in the formation of the Endowment. Elihu Root (1845-1937) served his country as Secretary of War, Secretary of State, and United States Senator. He is best remembered for his efforts to ensure international peace. He received the Nobel Peace prize in 1912 and was President of the Board of Trustees of the Carnegie Endowment from 1910 to 1925. Nicholas Murray Butler (1862-1947) served as President of Columbia University from 1902 to 1945 and shared the Nobel Peace Prize with Jane Addams in 1931. He succeeded Root as President of the Endowment, a post he held until 1945. The efforts of these men established the direction of the Endowment which for eighty-five years has encouraged peace through educational enterprises that promote international understanding and the codification of international law.
The Carnegie Endowment was headquartered in Washington, D.C., until it moved to New York City in 1950. Prior to its move, the Endowment sought an institution to purchase its library to ensure that its materials would continue to be available to researchers. The library collection was sold to The George Washington University in the year of the Endowment's move. This constituted a major acquisition for the University considering that in the fiscal year 1949/50 the University provided a total of $15,000 for the purchase of library books. The 60,000 volume collection of books, pamphlets, and documents was at that time one of the finest assembled for the study of international relations and world peace, according to an official from the Library of Congress who appraised the collection.
The Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, which since 1983 has again been headquartered in Washington, D.C., continues the work begun by its founders. Elihu Root and Nicholas Murray Butler were activists in a segment of a larger peace movement both in the U.S. and abroad that had its roots in the later years of the nineteenth century. The men and women who founded societies devoted to world peace were generally the elite of society: educators, business leaders, clergymen, journalists, etc. Periods of domestic and political turmoil and uncertainty, both at home and abroad, spurred these people to work for the cause of peace, since the promise of lasting peace meant economic and social stability. Peace societies served as forums for a national elite who held themselves responsible for molding public opinion on a wide range of issues, among them the promotion of a foreign policy that would establish a peaceful means of arbitrating international disputes. This collection of pamphlets reflect these aims and is thus a very useful research source for scholars.
Collection Scope and Content
This collection consists of over 7,200 items of bound pamphlets, unbound pamphlets, and microfilm. They range in date from 1817 to 1950. The collection covers more than following topics: the World Peace Foundation, World War I, World War II, the League of Nations, the League of Nations Union, the Treaty of Versailles, miscellaneous war, the New York Federation of Churches, International relations, national, regional, political science, social systems, economics, finance, foreign trade, labor, miscellaneous, and foreign language.
Gelman Library purchased this collection in 1950.
Please note there is no series one in this collection.
Collection Organization
Organized into four series (numbered 2-5): Library records, Unbound pamphlets, Microfilm, Bound manuscripts, and James B. Scott materials. Please note, there is no series one in this collection.
Washington (D.C.); Labor and laboring classes; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1939-1945; Treaty of Versailles (1919); Economic conditions; Finance; Butler, Nicholas Murray; Carnegie Endowment for International Peace; League of Nations Union; Carnegie, Andrew; League of Nations; World Peace Foundation; Root, Elihu
- Unbound pamphlets, 1817-1950; MS2110 Series 2; 47 Linear feet
  Scope and Contents note
  Please note there is no series one in this collection. This series contains approximately 4,350 unbound pamphlets, which include approximately 700 in foreign languages. They range in date from 1817 to 1950. Most of these fall under the "General Peace" category (about 19% of the total collection), "World War II" (13%), "National/Regional" (13%), and "International Relations/Foreign Policy" (4%). The remainder of the collection contains materials on political science, social science, economics, foreign trade, labor, and other subjects.
  - "A League of Peace", 1907 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    General note
    Previous folder number: A-2-1, Author: Carnegie, Andrew
  - "The Path to Peace", 1909 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Previous folder number: A-2-2, Author: Carnegie, Andrew
  - "Peace by Arbitration", 1907 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Previous folder number: A-2-3, Author: Carnegie, Andrew
  - "A League of Peace: A Rectorial Address", 1906 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    Previous folder number: A-2-4, Author: Carnegie, Andrew
  - "The Wrong Path"and "Armaments and Their Results", 1909 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Previous folder number: A-2-5, Author: Carnegie, Andrew (2 pamphlets)
  - Consecration Serviced Preceding the Opening of the International Peace Congress", 1904 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Previous folder number: A-2-6
  - "A Strong Army in a Free State", 1900 ca. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Previous folder number: A-2-7, Author: Coulton, G.G.
  - "Proved Practicability of International Arbitration", 1904 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Previous folder number: A-2-8, Author: Darby, W. Evans
  - "The Colleges and International Arbitration", 1910 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Previous folder number: A-2-9, Author: Harry, Clinton Phillips
  - "Justice Versus Force", 1900 ca. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Previous folder number: A-2-10, Author: International Arbitration and Peace Association
  - "America and the Hague Conferences" (Maryland Quarterly, no. 2), 1910 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Previous folder number: A-2-11, Author: Maryland Peace Society
  - "Judicial Proceedings as a Substitute for War or International Self-Redress" (Maryland Quarterly, no. 1), 1910 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Previous folder number: A-2-12, Author: Maryland Peace Society
  - "The Peace Movement Practical" (Maryland Quarterly, no. 4), 1910 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Previous folder number: A-2-13, Author: Maryland Peace Society
  - "War and Its Remedy" (Maryland Quarterly, no. 3), 1910 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Previous folder number: A-2-14, Author: Maryland Peace Society
  - "Jean de Bloch and the Future of War", 1903 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    Previous folder number: A-2-15, Author: Mead, Edwin D.
  - "More Earnest Work for the World's Peace", 1902 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    Previous folder number: A-2-16, Author: Mead, Edwin D.
  - "A Primer of the Peace Movement", 1908 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    Previous folder number: A-2-17, Author: Mead, Mrs. Lucia Ames
  - "A Primer of the Peace Movement", 1909 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    Previous folder number: A-2-18, Author: Mead, Lucia Ames
  - "Teaching Patriotism and Justice", 1907 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    Previous folder number: A-2-19, Author: Mead, Mrs. Lucia Ames
  - "American Prophets of Peace", 1907 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    Previous folder number: A-2-20, Author: National Arbitration and Peace Congress
  - "Armaments and Policy", 1909 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    Previous folder number: A-2-21, Author: National Peace Council (Political Series No.3)
  - "England and Germany" (Political Series No.2), 1908 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    Previous folder number: A-2-22, Author: National Peace Council
  - "Peace by Justice" (Political Series No.1), 1908 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    Previous folder number: A-2-23, Author: National Peace Council
  - "Teachers and International Peace", 1908 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    Previous folder number: A-2-24, Author: National Peace Council No.25
  - "New England Arbitration and Peace Congress", 1910 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    Previous folder number: A-2-25, Author: New England Peace Conference
  - "First Annual Report 1906" (Box 1, Folder 26)
    Previous folder number: A-2-26, Author: The Peace Society Australian Branch
  - "Jean de Bloch and the Museum of War and Peace", 1902 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    Previous folder number: A-2-27, Author: Perris, G.H.
  - "The Duty of Working for International Unity and Concord: A Letter to Unitarians", 1900 ca. (Box 1, Folder 28)
    Previous folder number: A-2-28, Author: Pratt, Hodgson
  - "Address by the Secretary of State, Mr. Root, Upon the Opening of the National Arbitration and Peace Congress, In the City of New York, April 15, 1907" (Box 1, Folder 29)
    Previous folder number: A-2-29, Author: Root, Elihu
  - "Seitz System of Governments - United Republics of the World", 1901 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    Previous folder number: A-2-30, Author: Seitz, Earl William
  - "To Abolish War", 1916 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    Previous folder number: A-2-31, Author: Stead, F. Herbert
  - "Cause and Cure of Modern Militarism", 1909 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    Previous folder number: A-2-32, Author: Tolstoy, Count
  - "International Arbitration at the Opening of the Twentieth Century", 1909 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    Previous folder number: A-2-33, Author: Trueblood, Benjamin F.
  - "A Periodic Congress of the Nations", 1907 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    Previous folder number: A-2-34, Author: Trueblood, Benjamin F.
  - "The Waste of Militarism", 1910 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    Previous folder number: A-2-35, Author: World Peace Foundation
  - "International Justice vs. 'The Splendors of War'", 1907 (Box 1, Folder 36)
    Previous folder number: A-2-36, Author: Wright, Carroll Davidson
  - "Letter and Tablet from Abdul-Baha to the Central Organization for a Durable Peace, Hague (Netherlands)", 1920 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    Previous folder number: A-3-1, Author:Abd Al-Baha Ibn Baha Allah
  - "Militarism as a Cause of the High Cost of Living", 1910 ca. (Box 1, Folder 38)
    Previous folder number: A-3-2, Author:The American Peace Society
  - "Report of the Inaugural Meeting", 1911 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    Previous folder number: A-3-3, Author:The American Peace Society of Japan
  - "The Policy Behind Armaments", 1911 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    Previous folder number: A-3-4, Author:Angell, Norman
  - "War and the Workers", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    Previous folder number: A-3-5, Author:Angell, Norman
  - "The Palace of Peace", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    Previous folder number: A-3-6, Author:Carnegie, Andrew
  - "The Promotion of International Peace through Universities", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    Previous folder number: A-3-7, Author:Carpenter, Jestlin
  - "The Causes of War", 1920 ca. (Box 1, Folder 44)
    Previous folder number: A-3-8, Author:Church Peace Union
  - "Europe's War America's Way", 1920 ca. (Box 1, Folder 45)
    Previous folder number: A-3-9, Author:Church Peace Union
  - "The Scourge of Militarism", 1920 ca. (Box 1, Folder 46)
    Previous folder number: A-3-10, Author:Church Peace Union
  - "The Way to Disarm: A Practical Proposal", 1920 ca. (Box 1, Folder 47)
    Previous folder number: A-3-11, Author:Church Peace Union
  - "The Second Hague Conference", 1915 ca. (Box 1, Folder 48)
    Previous folder number: A-3-12, Author:Darby, W. Evans
  - "War or Arbitration", 1912 ca. (Box 1, Folder 49)
    Previous folder number: A-3-13, Author:Dean of Gibraltar
  - "A Memorial to the President", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    Previous folder number: A-3-14, Author:Dutch Peace Society (Vrede door Recht)
  - "The United Democratic Nations of the World", 1917 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    Previous folder number: A-3-15, Author:Foote, Allen Ripley
  - "War on War", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 52)
    Previous folder number: A-3-16, Author:Forbes, Mrs. J. Malcolm
  - "The Peace Movement Among the Young", 1911 (Box 1, Folder 53)
    Previous folder number: A-3-17, Author:Gould, F.J.
  - "The Importance of Instruction", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 54)
    Previous folder number: A-3-18, Author:Hobson, John
  - "Peace Bibliography", 1910 (Box 1, Folder 55)
    Previous folder number: A-3-19, Author:Huntsman, M.H.
  - "War?? or Judicial Settlement of International Disputes?"(A Reply to Dr. James Brown Scott), 1914 (Box 1, Folder 56)
    Previous folder number: A-3-20, Author:Johannsen, N., (2 copies)
  - "An Open Letter to the Nation with Regard to a Peace Plan", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 57)
    Previous folder number: A-3-21, Author:Kehler, James Howard
  - "The Spirit of History Teaching Attitude of the Teacher Toward War", 1920 ca. (Box 1, Folder 58)
    Previous folder number: A-3-22, Author:Leuliette, Victor
  - "Twentieth World Peace Congress - Hague (Netherlands) President's Address", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 59)
    Previous folder number: A-3-23, Author:Louter, J. De
  - "Krause's League for Human Right and Thereby World Peace", 1917 (Box 1, Folder 60)
    Previous folder number: A-3-24, Author:MacCauley, Clay
  - "The Growth of the Pacific Spirit", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 61)
    Previous folder number: A-3-25, Author:Macdonnell, John
  - "A Forward Step in Civilization" (Maryland Quarterly, no. 9), 1912 (Box 1, Folder 62)
    Previous folder number: A-3-26, Author:Maryland Peace Society
  - "Internationalism as a Science" by Henri La Fonataine (Maryland Quarterly, no. 9), 1912 (Box 1, Folder 63 item 1)
    Previous folder number: A-3-27, Author:Maryland Peace Society
  - "The Poor" by - J.W. Magruder (Maryland Quarterly, no. 9), 1912 (Box 1, Folder 63 item 2)
  - "A League of Peace" (Maryland Quarterly, no. 7), 1911 (Box 1, Folder 64)
    Previous folder number: A-3-28, Author:Maryland Peace Society
  - "The Phases of Progress toward Peace" (Maryland Quarterly, no. 12), 1912 (Box 1, Folder 65)
    Previous folder number: A-3-29, Author:Maryland Peace Society
  - "The Waste of War" (Maryland Quarterly, no. 6), 1911 (Box 1, Folder 66)
    Previous folder number: A-3-30, Author:Maryland Peace Society
  - "Constitution for World-Wide Federation", 1911 (Box 1, Folder 67)
    Previous folder number: A-3-31, Author:Mason, Robert W.
  - "The False Mysticism of War", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 68)
    Previous folder number: A-3-32, Author:Matters, Muriel
  - "The American Peace Party and its Present Aims and Duties", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 69)
    Previous folder number: A-3-33, Author:Mead, Edwin
  - "Julia Ward Howe's Peace Crusade", 1910 (Box 1, Folder 70)
    Previous folder number: A-3-34, Author:Mead, Edwin D.
  - "Shall Great Britain, Germany, and the United States Now Unite for the Limitation of Naval Armaments?", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 71 item 1)
    Previous folder number: A-3-35, Author:Mead, Edwin D.
  - "Human Nature and the War System", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 71 item 2)
  - "Neutrality and Public Opinion", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    Previous folder number: A-3-36, Author:Nagel, Hon. Charles
  - "Neutrality and Public Opinion", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    Previous folder number: A-3-37, Author:Nagel, Hon. Charles
  - "Organized Insanity or the Hague", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    Previous folder number: A-3-38, Author:Nasmyth, George W.
  - "Arbitration and Sovereignty", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    Previous folder number: A-3-39, Author:National Peace Council, Baty, T.
  - "International Federation", 1911 (Box 1, Folder 76)
    Previous folder number: A-3-40, Author:National Peace Council, Alexander, Joseph G.
  - "Justice Not Force", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 77)
    Previous folder number: A-3-41, Author:National Peace Council, Rowntree, Joshua
  - "The International Peace Bureau and the Reconstruction of the International Movement", 1919 (Box 1, Folder 78)
    Previous folder number: A-3-42, Author:National Peace Council
  - "The International Peace Movement and the Present Crisis", 1918 (Box 1, Folder 79)
    Previous folder number: A-3-43, Author:National Peace Council
  - "The Policy of the National Peace Council Before and Since the Armistice", 1920 (Box 1, Folder 80)
    Previous folder number: A-3-44, Author:National Peace Council
  - "The Third Hague Conference and Innocent Commerce in time of War", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 81)
    Previous folder number: A-3-45, Author:National Peace Council, Lawrence, T.J.
  - "The Approach of Nations", 1911 (Box 1, Folder 82)
    Previous folder number: A-3-46, Author:National Peace Council, Newman, T.P.
  - "The Germs of War", 1916 (Box 1, Folder 83)
    Previous folder number: A-3-47, Author:Nearing, Scott
  - "On Behalf of the Coming Peace" (and additional pamphlets), 1914 (Box 1, Folder 84)
    Previous folder number: A-3-48, Author:Nederlandshe Anti-Oorlog Raad
  - "The Future of International Law", 1917 ca. (Box 1, Folder 85)
    Previous folder number: A-3-49, Author:Partridge, Frank C.
  - "International Peace Winning Essays", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 86)
    Previous folder number: A-3-50, Author:Peter, Eunice and Katherine Warren
  - "Social Reform Versus War", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 87)
    Previous folder number: A-3-51, Author:Porsonby, Arthur
  - "Should the Carnegie Foundation be Suppressed?", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 88)
    Previous folder number: A-3-52, Author:Pritchett, President Henry S.
  - "Some Supposed Just Causes of War", 1910 (Box 1, Folder 89)
    Previous folder number: A-3-53, Author:Ralston, Jackson H.
  - "A Nation in Arms", 1912 (Box 1, Folder 90)
    Previous folder number: A-3-54, Author:Roberts, Frederick
  - "The Great Evolution and End of War", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    Previous folder number: A-3-55, Author:Ross, John Milton
  - "Universities and the Peace Movement", 1911 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    Previous folder number: A-3-56, Author:Seth, James
  - "Why we Should not Increase Our Armaments", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    Previous folder number: A-3-57, Author:Sharpless, Isaac
  - "The Near-At-Hand World League for Prevention of Aggression", 1916 (Box 1, Folder 94)
    Previous folder number: A-3-58, Author:Shibley, George H.
  - "The Present Status of International Arbitration - Winning Essay", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 95)
    Previous folder number: A-3-59, Author:Smith, Bryant
  - "An Argument Against The League To Enforce Peace - Cooperation Versus Compulsion in the Organization of the Society of Nations", 1916 (Box 1, Folder 96)
    Previous folder number: A-3-60, Author:Snow, Alpheus H.
  - "The Federation of Nations", 1917 ca. (Box 1, Folder 97)
    Previous folder number: A-3-61, Author:The Society for the Promotion of the Federation of Nations
  - "The Case for an International Police Force", 1919 ca. (Box 1, Folder 98)
    Previous folder number: A-3-62, Author:Stead, F. Herbert
  - "War and the Need of a Higher Nationalism", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 99)
    Previous folder number: A-3-63, Author:Symonds, Rev. H.
  - "The Historic Development of the Peace Idea", 1913 (Box 1, Folder 100)
    Previous folder number: A-3-64, Author:Trueblood, Benjamin Franklin
  - "Theories of Social Organization and the Problems of International Peace", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 101)
    Previous folder number: A-3-65, Author:Tenney, A.A.
  - "The End of War and the Federation of the Peoples", 1911 ca. (Box 1, Folder 102)
    Previous folder number: A-3-66, Author:Umano
  - "Union of Democratic Controle", 1918 ca. (Box 1, Folder 103)
    Previous folder number: A-3-67, Author:Union of Democratic Controle, [German, Swedish, Dutch, French, Italian]
  - "The Union of International Associations - A World Center", 1914 (Box 1, Folder 104)
    Previous folder number: A-3-68, Author:Union of International Associations
  - "Speech Delivered by the German Chancellor Dr. Von Bethmann-Hooweg", 1916 (Box 1, Folder 105)
    Previous folder number: A-3-69, Author:Von Bethmann-Hollweg, Dr.
  - "War or Peace", 1915 (Box 1, Folder 106)
    Previous folder number: A-3-70
  - "Humane Teaching and International Peace", 1910 (Box 1, Folder 107)
    Previous folder number: A-3-71, Author:Weardale, Lord
  - "America and the Permanent Court of International Justice", 1910 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Previous folder number: A-3-72, Author:World Peace Foundation
  - "Annual Report 1916", 1917 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    Previous folder number: A-3-73, Author:World Peace Foundation
  - "Club Women and the Peace Movement", 1912 ca. (Box 2, Folder 3)
    Previous folder number: A-3-74, Author:World Peace Foundation
  - "Instructions to the American Delegates to the Hague Conferences 1899 and 1907", 1913 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    Previous folder number: A-3-75, Author:World Peace Foundation
  - "Leaflets on Preparedness", 1915 ca. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    Previous folder number: A-3-76, Author:World Peace Foundation
  - "The New Pan Americanism", 1917 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    Previous folder number: A-3-77, Author:World Peace Foundation
  - "If War Were A Crime", 1925 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    Previous folder number: A-4-1, Author:Allen, Florence E.
  - "International Conciliation", 1923 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    Previous folder number: A-4-2, Author:American Association for International Conciliation
  - "Letter of Salmon O. Levinson to Mr. J.C. Garnett" (Box 2, Folder 9)
    Previous folder number: A-4-3, Author:American Committee for the Outlawry of War
  - Miscellaneous Pamphlets, 1922-1929 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    Previous folder number: A-4-5, Author:American Peace Society
  - "The Effort of the United Stated to Bring About World Peace", 1924 ca. (Box 2, Folder 11)
    Previous folder number: A-4-6, Author:Boeckel, Florence Brewer
  - "The Effort of the United States to Bring About World Peace", 1927 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    Previous folder number: A-4-7, Author:Boeckel, Florence Brewer
  - "The Power of the Press for Peace and War", 1924 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    Previous folder number: A-4-8, Author:Boeckel, Florence Brewer
  - "Outlawry of War", 1923 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    Previous folder number: A-4-9, Author:Borah, William E.
  - "Public Opinion Outlaws War", 1924 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    Previous folder number: A-4-10, Author:Borah, William E. (2 copies)
  - "Reparations and Public Opinion" Foreign Policy Association No.20, 1923 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    Previous folder number: A-4-11, Author:Boyden, Ronald W.
  - "Construction of Cruisers", 1929 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    Previous folder number: A-4-12, Author:Burton, Theodore E.
  - "The Disarmament Conference at Washington Will be a Failure", 1921 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    Previous folder number: A-4-13, Author:Carnovale, Luigi
  - "Only By the Abolition of Neutrality Can Wars be Quickly and Forever Prevented", 1922 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    Previous folder number: A-4-14, Author:Carnovale, Luigi